Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：
是的，是的，船长。
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
SpongeBob: Seven, six, five,
four, three, two...
海绵宝宝：七、六、五、
四、三、二……
whoa-Oh!
哇哦！
Open for business.
开门营业。
Yeah, whoo.
是的，呼。
Oh, Mr. Krabs, Mr. Krabs,
can I do it today?
哦，蟹老板，蟹老板，
我今天可以做吗？
Uuh-huh, can I, can I do it?
呃呃，我可以吗，我可以吗？
I suppose you can
have the honor today, lad.
我想你可以
今天很荣幸，小伙子。
Whoo.
呼。
37, 38 --
37, 38——
37、38——
Freshness, check.
新鲜度，检查一下。
Buns, check.
包子，检查一下。
Fresh patties...
新鲜的肉饼...
Check.
查看。
Oh, silly me.
哦，愚蠢的我。
I'm forgetting
one more minor detail.
我忘记了
还有一个小细节。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
Is it getting hot in here?
这里变热了吗？
Or is it just you?
或者只是你？
Ah.
啊。
"Two Krabby Patties.
“两个蟹肉饼。
P.S. SpongeBob, you're an idiot.
附：海绵宝宝，你是个白痴。
Love, Squidward."
爱你，章鱼哥。”
Oh, love you too, Squiddy.
哦，我也爱你，鱿鱼。
Two Krabby Patties
comin' right up.
两块蟹肉饼
马上就来了。
Whoa.
哇哦。
Hmm...
唔...
Got ya.
明白了。
Hoo, this thing
is stuck pretty good.
呼，这个东西
卡得很好。
I guess this is it.
我想就是这样了。
Oh, you really saved me.
噢，你真的救了我。
Hey, a splinter.
嘿，一个碎片。
Ok, well it's been nice knowing
ya, but you've got to go... Now.
好的，很高兴知道
是的，但你必须走……现在。
OK, out we go.
好的，我们出发吧。
Whoa, that kind of hurts.
哇，那种感觉很痛。
Come on,  ,
whoa, that really hurts.
来吧，，
哇，真的很痛。
Oh, barnacles, this hurts.
哦，藤壶，这很疼。
Conch-shelled manatees,
this is painful!
海螺壳海牛，
这很痛苦！
OK, you're tough, you're smart
and you are charming.
好吧，你很坚强，你很聪明
你很迷人。
But you are
still no match for me.
但你是
还是不敌我。
Look, a bald eagle
with a moustache.
看，一只秃鹰
留着小胡子。
OK, fine, stay.
好吧，好吧，留下来。
But I hope you like
making Krabby Patties.
但我希望你喜欢
制作蟹黄饼。
Excuse me, sir, but, um...
对不起，先生，但是，嗯...
I ordered a couple
Krabby Patties a while ago
我订了一对
不久前的蟹肉饼
and, uh, I'm wondering
when they'll be out.
而且，呃，我想知道
他们什么时候出来。
Looks like I'm crushing
your face.
看来我要崩溃了
你的脸。
So will they be ready soon?
那么他们很快就会准备好吗？
Yeah-yeah-yeah, don't move
too much, it ruins it.
是啊是啊，别动
太多了，就会毁了它。
Ow, ow, ow.
噢，噢，噢。
You're making this
a little bit difficult.
你正在做这个
有点困难。
Luckily, I am ambidextrous.
幸运的是，我双手灵巧。
Perfection.
完美。
I hear you, I hear you.
我听到你的声音，我听到你的声音。
Ok, good, 'cause these two
Krabby Patties are ready.
好吧，很好，因为这两个人
蟹黄饼就准备好了。
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
Yes?
是的？
Can I ask you something?
我能问你一件事吗？
Yes.
是的。
What's that?
那是什么？
What's what?
什么是什么？
You know.
你知道。
Know what?
知道什么吗？
This.
这。
This thing here.
这东西在这里。
What thing where?
什么东西在哪里？
The spatula  tied to your nose!
抹刀绑在你的鼻子上！
This.
这。
Well, you see,
this got stuck up there.
嗯，你看，
这被卡在那里了。
So I stacked stuff
and I climbed up to reach it.
所以我把东西堆起来
我爬上去到达了那里。
I reached to grab it,
I got it, but then I fell
我伸手去抓它，
我明白了，但后来我跌倒了
and I screamed!
我尖叫起来！
I was sure I was dead,
but then I wasn't.
我确信我已经死了
但后来我就不是了。
But then I tripped and I got
this splinter, uh, Squidward?
但后来我绊倒了
这块碎片，呃，章鱼哥？
Squidward, were you
listening at all?
章鱼哥，你是
到底在听吗？
I got this really bad
splinter, you see?
我真的很糟糕
碎片，你看到了吗？
And I couldn't hold the spatula
with my hand, so I used my nose.
我拿不住抹刀
用手，所以我用鼻子。
Makes sense now, right?
现在有道理了，对吧？
Oh, yeah, that
makes perfect sense.
哦，是的，那个
很有道理。
You're a halfwit who injured
himself at work being a nitwit.
你是个受伤的傻瓜
他自己在工作中就是个白痴。
Good one, Squiddy.
好一个，乌贼。
D'oh, injury,
your brain is injured.
哎呀，受伤了，
你的大脑受伤了。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
Did you say you got that
splinter injury at work?
你说你明白了吗
工作中受到碎片伤害？
Yeah.
是的。
Oh,  ,
that's not good.
哦，，
那不好。
I know, it hurts so bad.
我知道，这太痛了。
Yeah, when Mr. Krabs
finds out, oh, man.
是的，当蟹老板
发现，哦，伙计。
Finds out what?
发现了什么？
Finds out about this injury.
了解了这次受伤的情况。
You mean my splinter?
你是说我的碎片吗？
He'll be forced to
send you home.
他将被迫
送你回家。
H-H-H-Home, but I'm fine.
回家了，但我很好。
Here, let me take this for you.
在这里，让我替你拿这个。
Why?
为什么？
Hey, wait, I'm fine.
嘿，等等，我很好。
It was a good shift
while it lasted.
这是一个很好的转变
当它持续的时候。
While it lasted,
what are you doing?
当它持续的时候，
你在做什么？
W-W-W-What are you?
W-W-W-你是什么？
I know it's hard
to say good-Bye.
我知道这很难
说再见。
But, but Squidward, I'm fine.
但是，但是章鱼哥，我很好。
♪ I'm fine, I'm ok ♪
♪ 我很好，我很好 ♪
♪ Look at me, nothing's wrong ♪
♪ 看看我，没什么问题 ♪
See, see, see, see?
看，看，看，看？
Oh, I believe you, SpongeBob.
哦，我相信你，海绵宝宝。
But unfortunately,
the rules clearly state
that you must be sent home.
但不幸的是，
规则明确规定
你必须被送回家。
No, anything but that.
不，除此之外什么都没有。
Please, Squidward,
you can't let this happen.
求你了，章鱼哥，
你不能让这种事发生。
You can't let them
force me away.
你不能让他们
强行把我赶走。
Sorry, the rules are the rules.
抱歉，规则就是规则。
Yeah, it'll be
pretty quiet around here
是的，将会是
这里很安静
with Mr. Krabs sending you
home early and all.
蟹老板送你去
早点回家。
I just hope we'll make it
through the whole rest of
this day without you here.
我只是希望我们能成功
通过整个其余的
没有你的这一天。
Please, Squidward.
求你了，章鱼哥。
Don't tell Mr. Krabs.
别告诉蟹老板先生。
What, me tell Mr. Krabs?
什么，我告诉蟹老板？
Oh, no...
哦，不...
No, no, no, no-no-no-no.
不，不，不，不不不不。
No, no, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不，不。
No, no, no-no-no-no.
不，不，不不不不。
No.
不。
Whew.
呼。
Well, maybe.
嗯，也许吧。
I don't have to tell Mr. Krabs.
我不必告诉蟹老板。
Because
he already knows.
因为
他已经知道了。
He does?
他有吗？
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
Krabs has preternatural
instincts when it comes to
situations like this.
螃蟹有超自然的能力
当涉及到时的本能
像这样的情况。
It's almost as if
when something's amiss
in his restaurant...
几乎就像
当出现问题时
在他的餐厅里...
He can smell it.
他能闻到。
These quarters smell sad.
这些宿舍闻起来很悲伤。
You're not planning on getting
a refill with 'em, are you?
你不打算得到
补充一下，是吗？
No, I wasn't.
不，我不是。
You're right, Squidward,
I need help.
你说得对，章鱼哥，
我需要帮助。
Please pick up, please pick up,
please pick up.
请接机，请接机，
请接。
Patrick?
帕特里克？
Yeah?
是的？
Ah, thank goodness you're there.
啊，谢天谢地你在那儿。
I got a splinter
in my thumb and...
我有一个碎片
在我的拇指和...
Mm-hmm, I see.
嗯嗯，我明白了。
Well, I'm pretty booked today.
嗯，今天我的预约已经满了。
But I think I can fit you in.
但我想我可以适应你。
Thanks, Patrick.
谢谢，帕特里克。
No problem.
没问题。
You called the right person,
Mr. SpongeBob.
你给对的人打电话了，
海绵宝宝先生。
Now let's see where
the problem's at.
现在让我们看看在哪里
问题出在。
Hmm, interesting.
嗯，有趣。
Uh, Patrick?
呃，帕特里克？
Hmm, interesting.
嗯，有趣。
Patrick...
帕特里克...
Patrick, this isn't helping.
帕特里克，这没有帮助。
Oh, I'm sorry.
哦，对不起。
I didn't realize
you were a doctor, humph.
我没有意识到
你是一名医生，哼。
I'm not.
我不是。
Oh, but I'm sure you can
figure it out with your
12 years of med school.
哦，但我相信你可以
和你一起弄清楚
12年医学院学习经历。
Patrick, you didn't
go to med school.
帕特里克，你没有
去医学院。
So?
所以？
Patrick, I'm sorry,
I really need your help.
帕特里克，对不起，
我真的需要你的帮助。
Oh, no, no, it looks like
you have things under control.
噢不不，看起来像
你一切尽在掌控之中。
Please, Patrick,
I don't want to go home early.
拜托，帕特里克，
我不想早点回家。
OK, but we play by
my rules, "SquareBob."
好吧，但我们玩的是
我的规则是“SquareBob”。
Well, here's your problem.
好吧，这就是你的问题。
But don't you worry, buddy.
但别担心，伙计。
We're gonna make it go away.
我们要让它消失。
Ah, thanks, Patrick,
you're a lifesaver.
啊，谢谢，帕特里克，
你是救星。
Ow.
噢。
There appears to be
a little bit of swelling.
似乎有
有点肿胀。
This garbage compress
should help that go down.
这个垃圾压缩
应该有助于下降。
That doesn't look good.
那看起来不太好。
Yeah, but my shift is over.
是的，但我的轮班已经结束了。
Call me in the morning...
早上给我打电话...
If you can still dial a phone.
如果还能拨打电话的话。
What's that?
那是什么？
What's what?
什么是什么？
Behind your back.
在你背后。
You mean... This?
你是说……这个？
Put your hat on, boy,
show some company pride.
戴上你的帽子，孩子，
表现出一些公司的自豪感。
Ah, company pride, of course.
啊，当然是公司的自豪感。
Uh, SpongeBob?
呃，海绵宝宝？
Yes?
是的？
Have you always had three legs?
你一直都是三足的吗？
Yes.
是的。
Interesting.
有趣的。
Well, what's this about
a splinter that Squidward's been
telling me all about?
嗯，这是关于什么的
章鱼哥曾经的碎片
告诉我一切？
All right, boy, let's see it.
好吧，孩子，让我们看看吧。
Come on, SpongeBob,
it's just a little splinter.
来吧，海绵宝宝，
I mean, how bad could it...
我的意思是，这能有多糟糕...
Oh, merciful Neptune.
哦，仁慈的海王星。
OK, no problem, no problem.
好的，没问题，没问题。
Problem...
问题...
Whew, for a second there
哇，一会儿
I thought I was gonna
have to pay you
workman's "compersation."
我以为我会
必须付钱给你
工人的“补偿”。
What's workers' compensation?
什么是工人赔偿？
You know, when you get
paid for sitting at home.
你知道，当你得到
支付坐在家里的费用。
You mean I can get paid
while I'm at home?
你的意思是我可以获得报酬
当我在家的时候？
Yeah, what do you think
"compersation" stands for?
是的，你觉得怎么样
“补偿”代表什么？
Uh... Squidward?
呃……章鱼哥？
I get my "compersation" now?
我现在得到“补偿”了吗？
Nope, sorry, Squidward,
your shift ended over
two minutes ago.
不，对不起，章鱼哥，
你的轮班结束了
两分钟前。
Huh, what's that?
哈，那是什么？
Hmm, must be hearing things.
嗯，一定是听到了什么。
Ah, smell that
fresh morning sea.
啊，闻那个味道
清新的早晨海。
Huh, must be
hearing things... Again.
呵呵，一定是
再次听到一些事情。
Whew.
呼。
What is that noise?
那是什么噪音？
I should have guessed.
我早该猜到的。
It's too early for this.
现在说这个还为时过早。
All right, you two.
好吧，你们两个。
What is the meaning of this?
这有什么意义呢？
"What is the meaning of this?"
“这是什么意思？”
We're slide-whistling.
我们吹着口哨滑行。
Don't you mean playing
the slide whistle?
你不是说玩吗
幻灯片哨子？
Squidward, slide-whistling is
more than just simply
tooting on an instrument.
章鱼哥，滑口哨是
不仅仅是简单的
吹奏乐器。
It's a way of life.
这是一种生活方式。
Let's show him, Patrick.
让我们展示给他看，帕特里克。
Squidward: Hey, get out of here.
章鱼哥：嘿，离开这里。
Huh?
啊？
All right, you two morons,
show yourselves.
好吧，你们两个白痴，
展示你自己。
You see, Squidward.
你看，章鱼哥。
Slide-whistling can add
a little zest to the humdrum
of everyday life.
滑哨可以加
给单调带来一点热情
日常生活的。
I don't need zest.
我不需要热情。
I need you out of my lampshade.
我需要你离开我的灯罩。
What?
什么？
Get out of there!
离开那里！
Just get out of there.
离开那里吧。
OK, that's enough,
you've had your fun.
好吧，够了，
你玩得很开心。
True, Squidward, true.
是的，章鱼哥，是的。
We have had our fun.
我们玩得很开心。
But you know what's
twice as much fun?
但你知道什么是
两倍的乐趣？
Twice as many slide whistles.
幻灯片哨声的数量是原来的两倍。
After you, my good man.
在你之后，我的好人。
Thanks, buddy.
谢谢，伙计。
Not the windows again.
又不是窗户了。
Got ya.
明白了。
They're gone, whew.
他们走了，哇。
Now if they would just
stay out of my house
现在如果他们愿意
离我家远点
I might be able to enjoy
a little squid time.
我或许可以享受
一点鱿鱼时间。
Huh?
啊？
I gotta get out of here!
我得离开这里！
Look, Patrick, Squidward's
finally playing along.
看，帕特里克，章鱼哥
终于一起玩了
Go away!
离开！
Can't you idiots take a hint?
你们这些白痴就不能指点一下吗？
I think I lost 'em.
我想我失去了他们。
Huh?
啊？
How would you like it
if someone did this to you?
你想要怎样
如果有人这样对你？
All right.
好的。
Wow, Squidward.
哇，章鱼哥。
You have got quite
an ear for music.
你已经有相当
一只听音乐的耳朵。
Don't you- I do?
你不——我不吗？
Yes, my friend,
you have got "the goods."
是的，我的朋友，
你已经得到了“货物”。
Well, uh, ha.
嗯，呃，哈。
That  is  true.
确实如此。
Come on, play some
more, maestro.
来吧，玩一些
更多，大师。
Me and Patrick want to
dance to your  sweet  tunes.
我和帕特里克想要
随着你甜美的曲调起舞。
Well...
出色地...
If you insist.
如果你坚持的话。
Oh, we insist.
哦，我们坚持。
OK...
好的...
Hello?
你好？
Well, that's unusual.
嗯，这很不寻常。
What is this?
这是什么？
Who's there?
谁在那里？
Who's back here?
谁回来了？
All right, this isn't funny.
好吧，这不好笑。
Come on, jerk, you think
you can mess with me?
来吧，混蛋，你认为
你能惹我吗？
Watch this.
注意这个。
Ah-ha.
啊哈。
Oh!
哦！
Someone, help, baby-assaulter.
来人啊，救命啊，袭击婴儿的人。
Man: Assault your own baby.
男：袭击你自己的孩子。
Where you going,
hey, come back here.
你要去哪里，
嘿，回到这里。
If you say so.
如果你这么说的话。
Patrick, are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
帕特里克，你在想吗
我在想什么？
Probably not.
可能不会。
Woman: Oh, honey, I'm so sorry.
女：哦，亲爱的，我很抱歉。
I promise it'll
never happen again.
我保证会的
永远不会再发生。
Can I help you?
我可以帮你吗？
Liar!
说谎者！
Man: She's not lying.
男：她没有说谎。
She speaks the truth.
她说的是实话。
Someone wicked has disturbed
our peaceful city, Frank.
有人不法分子扰乱
我们和平的城市，弗兰克。
But who would do such a thing?
但谁会做这样的事呢？
Squidward, Squidward Tentacles.
章鱼哥，章鱼哥触手。
He lives on conch Drive.
他住在海螺大道上。
What?
什么？
Yes, we must capture him.
是的，我们必须抓住他。
He must pay for his wrongdoings.
他必须为他的错误行为付出代价。
Oh, he's gonna pay,
he's gonna pay with interest.
哦，他会付钱的，
他会连本带利地付钱。
He's going down.
他要下去了。
Come on, let's get him.
来吧，让我们抓住他。
Patrick, do you think Squidward
is taking this all too far?
帕特里克，你认为章鱼哥
这一切是否太过分了？
He's only a block away.
他距离我们只有一个街区。
what do you make of it, sarge?
你觉得怎么样，中士？
Looks like a full-scale riot.
看来是一场全面的骚乱。
I'm calling for back-Up,
get me the canine unit.
我正在呼叫支援，
给我拿个犬类单位。
Would you like some more?
您还想要更多吗？
Wait, wait, you stupid worms.
等等，等等，你们这些愚蠢的虫子。
I was supposed to
retire this week.
我本来应该
本周退休。
Let's give 'em a grand finale
they'll never forget.
让我们给他们一个盛大的结局
他们永远不会忘记。
Huh, what is that?
哈，那是什么？
I can't work
under these conditions.
我无法工作
在这些条件下。
Now you're in
the driver's seat, Squiddy.
现在你在
驾驶座，鱿鱼。
This is great.
这太棒了。
Well, Plankton finally got
what he deserved.
好吧，浮游生物终于得到了
他应得的。
Whoa...
哇...
Stop.
停止。
Ha, I've never felt
so alive.
哈，我从来没有感受过
如此活着。
I don't want to stop.
我不想停下来。
Um, Squidward?
嗯，章鱼哥？
Are you  sure  you don't
want to stop?
你确定你不
想停下来吗？
What are you
talking about, nitwit?
你是什么
在谈论，白痴？
Up ahead.
就在前面。
What "up ahead"?
什么“前面”？
Man: Justice!
男：正义！
Woman: Dr. Forrest,
dial 118, please, Dr. Forrest.
女：福雷斯特博士，
请拨打 118，福雷斯特博士。
Your friend is very lucky.
你的朋友很幸运。
If it wasn't for
that slide whistle
getting lodged in his throat
如果不是为了
那个幻灯片哨子
卡在喉咙里
the rescue team might have
never found him.
救援队可能有
从来没有找到他。
His yelling, or whistling,
I should say
他的叫喊或者吹口哨
我应该说
under all that rubble
saved his life.
在所有那些瓦砾下
救了他的命。
Doctor, why did you leave
the whistle in his throat?
医生，你为什么要离开？
他喉咙里的口哨声？
Unfortunately, we don't have
the technology to remove it yet.
不幸的是，我们没有
目前还没有技术来去除它。
But on the bright side, he can
still communicate with it.
但从好的方面来看，他可以
还是和它沟通。
Wow, Squidward, listen to you.
哇，章鱼哥，听你说。
You're getting better already.
你已经好起来了。
Here, we'll help.
在这里，我们会提供帮助。